Selim Maurice Franklin papers, 1873-1931
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
- Series II: Professional Papers, 1873-1927
  - Mining Case Files, 1880-1927
    - Reward and Casa Grande-Arizona Co.: Correspondence regarding various legal cases. (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - Brooks, Van H.: Correspondence. 1910-1924 (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Gadsden Copper Co.: Correspondence. 1913-1923 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Gadsden Copper Co.: Legal papers, miscellaneous material. 1913-1922 (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Gadsden Copper Co.: Stock certificates. 1913-1918 (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Gadsden Copper Co.: Stock Journal and Ledger. 1913-1914 (Box 31)
    - Gadsden Copper Co.: Stockholders' meetings, By-laws. 1913-1921 (Box 31)
      Also includes Casa Grande-Arizona Copper Co.
    - L. A. Snyder, Imperial Copper Co.: Correspondence. 1901-1902 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Imperial Copper Co.: Correspondence. 1903-1904, 1911-1925 (Box 32, Folder 2-5)
    - Imperial Copper Co.: Legal papers. 1904, 1911-1916 (Box 33, Folder 1-5)
    - Imperial Copper Co.: Related cases. 1912-1918 (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - Imperial Copper Co.: Taxes, receipts. 1911-1914 (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - Imperial Copper Co.: Miscellaneous. (Box 33, Folder 8)
    - Arizona Southern Railroad Co. regarding salary, passes, personal injury cases, and minutes of meetings. 1916-1924 (Box 33, Folder 9)
    - Southern Arizona Smelting Co.: Legal papers, etc. 1916-1918 (Box 33, Folder 10)
    - Mansfield Mining and Smelting Co.: Articles of Incorporation, Stockholders papers, financial records. 1907-1910 (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Mansfield Mining and Smelting Co.: Correspondence. 1904-1925 (Box 34, Folder 2-4)
    - Mansfield Mining and Smelting Co.: Legal case, R. R. Richardson. 1907-1910 (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - Mansfield Mining and Smelting Co.: Legal cases, Valenzuelo and Brash. 1910-1911 (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - Honet Mine: Location notices, abstract of title, etc. (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - Ruby Group: Location notices, abstract of title, etc. (Box 34, Folder 8)
    - Various Mines: Location notices, abstract of title, etc. (Box 34, Folder 9-10)
    - Ruby Copper Co. 1904-1920 (Box 34, Folder 11)
    - Southern Arizona Mining Co. 1912-1919 (Box 34, Folder 12)
    - Mile Wide Copper Co.: Correspondence. 1916, 1920-1927 (Box 35, Folder 1-3)
    - J. P. Piper, et al vs. Mile Wide Copper Co: Legal papers. 1920-1923 (Box 35, Folder 4-5)
    - Mile Wide Copper Co.: Various related cases. (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - Mile Wide Copper Co.: Miscellaneous notes, reports, etc. (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - Mile Wide Copper Co.: Abstract of Record and Statement of Facts in the Piper-Reiniger cases, Supreme Court of the State of Arizona. (Box 35)
    - North Mowry Mining Co.: Articles of Incorporation; minutes of meetings. (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - North Mowry Mining Co.: Correspondence. 1905-1924 (Box 36, Folder 2-3)
    - North Mowry Mining Co.: W. P. Savage correspondence. 1905-1907 (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - North Mowry Mining Co.: Legal papers. 1904-1924 (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - North Mowry Mining Co.: Taxes and financial records. 1911-1925 (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - North Mowry Mining Co.: Stock records and certificates. (Box 36, Folder 7)
    - North Mowry Mining Co.: Golden Gate Mine location notices, deeds, patent, map, etc. (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - North Mowry Mining Co.: James Brash, et al, vs. Francis Parke, et al. 1905-1906 (Box 36, Folder 9)
    - North Mowry Mining Co.: Letter Book. 1906-1907? (Box 36, Folder 10)
    - Continental Commission Co.: Articles of Incorporation, minutes, stockholders, etc. (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - 79 Mining Co.: Correspondence. 1920-1926 (Box 37, Folder 2-5)
    - 79 Mining Co.: Mine locations, deeds, maps. (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - 79 Mining Co.: Miscellaneous items. (Box 37, Folder 7)
    - 79 Mining Co.: Miscellaneous financial records. 1920-1923 (Box 37, Folder 8)
    - 79 Mining Co.: Abstract of Record of T. A. Harrison vs. Continental Commission Co., T. D. Love, 79 Mining Co., etc. in the Supreme Court of the State of Arizona. (Box 37)
    - Thomas Harrison vs. Continental Commission Co., 79 Mining Co., etc.: Legal papers. 1921-1924 (Box 38, Folder 1-4)
    - 79 Mining Co.: Miscellaneous notes, etc. (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - 79 Mining Co.: Draft of Abstract of Record. (Box 38)
    - South San Xavier Copper Co.: Correspondence. 1903-1924 (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - South San Xavier Copper Co.: Taxes and miscellaneous financial records. 1903-1923 (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - South San Xavier Copper Co.: Mine locations, deeds, patents. (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - South San Xavier Copper Co.: Stockholders, transactions, etc. (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - South San Xavier Copper Co.: Miscellaneous legal papers, Articles of Incorporation, Agreements, etc. (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - South San Xavier Copper Co.: Scrapbook of clippings regarding mines and mining. (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - South San Xavier Copper Co.: Maps, reports, miscellaneous papers. (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - South San Xavier Copper Co.: Minute Book for Board of Directors and Stockholders. 1906-1924 (Box 39)
    - South San Xavier Copper Co.: Transfer Journal and Stock Ledger. (Box 40)
    - South San Xavier Copper Co.: Stock certificates, no. 1-100. 1906-1907 (Box 40)
    - Tucson-Ray Arizona Copper Co.: Articles of Incorporation, Minutes of meetings. 1917-1924 (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - Tucson-Ray Arizona Copper Co.: Reports and correspondence. 1917-1924 (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - Tucson-Ray Arizona Copper Co.: Income taxes. 1918-1926 (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - Tucson-Ray Arizona Copper Co.: Stock certificates. (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - Salero Mines Co.: Correspondence. 1887-1910 (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Estate of Charles H. Ferry: Correspondence. 1910-1917 (Box 41, Folder 2-4)
    - Estate of Charles H. Ferry: Probate Court papers. 1910 (Box 41, Folder 5)
    - W. G. Dumont vs. Harry E. Heighton, Administrator, Estate of Charles H. Ferry. 1910-1912 (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - Estate of Charles H. Ferry: Related cases. 1908-1913 (Box 41, Folder 7)
    - Estate of Charles H. Ferry: Bills, receipts, financial records including some for the Ruby Gold and Copper Co. 1907-1910 (Box 41, Folder 8)
    - Estate of Charles H. Ferry: Constitution, Columbia, Happy Camp Mining Claims. (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - Estate of Charles H. Ferry: Eureka Group Mining Claims. (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - Estate of Charles H. Ferry: Santa Maria, Santa Cruz, Tiajuana Mining Claims. (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - Estate of Charles H. Ferry: Mine Locations, deeds, agreements, assay reports from various mines. (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - Estate of Charles H. Ferry: Dana Harmon Mineral Certificates. 1883-1892 (Box 42, Folder 5)
    - Estate of Junius Dana. 1907-1909 (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - Estate of William P. Blake. 1910-1914 (Box 42, Folder 7)
    - Baboquivari Mines: Chiefly correspondence with Charles A. Boake of Ohio. 1894-1897 (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - Brownell-Arizona Mining and Smelting Co. 1910-1925 (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - Cabrisa and Spring Mining Claims: T. Borton, et. al. vs. J. M. Martinez and J. Castillo. 1913 (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - Calumet and Copper Creek Mining Co.: Case involving Eagle Milling Co. 1914-1915 (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - Cerro Cobre Development Co.: Correspondence, etc. 1907-1927 (Box 43, Folder 5-6)
    - Cerro Cobre Development Co.: Legal cases with W. B. Duvall. 1910-1914 (Box 43, Folder 7)
    - Cerro Cobre Development Co.: Legal cases, various. (Box 43, Folder 8)
    - Chesterfield Copper Co.: Correspondence. 1909-1916 (Box 43, Folder 9)
    - H. N. Brown vs. Chesterfield Copper Co.: 1911-1915 (Box 43, Folder 10)
    - Cerro Colorado Mining and Milling Co.: Legal cases, various. 1907-1910 (Box 44, Folder 1)
      Suits brought by:
      J. Knox Corbett Lumber Co.
      Albert Steinfeld Co.
      Roy & Titcomb
      Twin Buttes Railroad Co.
      M. M. Carpenter
      Josephine L. Udall
    - Cerro Colorado Mining and Milling Co.: Bankruptcy. 1909 (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - H. Donau vs. Cerro Colorado Mining and Milling Co. 1908-1911 (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - Cerro Colorado Mines Co. 1909-1917 (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - San Nicholas Copper Co. 1910-1918 (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - Copper Belle Mining Co. 1903-1905 (Box 44, Folder 6)
    - Crown Consolidated Copper, Gold & Silver Mining Co. 1897-1900 (Box 44, Folder 7)
    - Doxology Group Mining Co.: Correspondence with H. H. North and Alexander von Wendt. 1893-1897 (Box 44, Folder 8)
    - Arizona Consolidated Mining Co.: Correspondence. 1905-1909 (Box 45, Folder 1-2)
    - Arizona Consolidated Mining Co.: Legal case, A. Steinfeld vs. Lingerman, et al. 1906-1908 (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - Arizona Consolidated Mining Co.: Legal case, Gardiner, et al, vs. Owen, et al. 1906-1908 (Box 45, Folder 4)
    - Arizona Consolidated Mining Co.: Legal cases, various. 1904-1908 (Box 45, Folder 5)
      Some cases involved the Sorrel Top Gold Mining and Milling Co. which merged into the Arizona Consolidated Mining Co. Suits brought by:
      A. Goldschmidt
      A. C. Lamb
      Llewellyn Iron Works
      Adrian Yepis
    - Arizona Consolidated Mining Co.: Debts, bankruptcy. 1903-1909 (Box 45, Folder 6)
    - El Tiro Copper Co. 1911, 1916-1927 (Box 45, Folder 7)
    - Wester American Mines Co. 1925-1927 (Box 45, Folder 8)
    - Exposed Reef Mining Co. 1900-1911 (Box 45, Folder 9)
    - Franco-American Mining and Milling Co. 1896-1898 (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - Gold Placer Company of Mexico. 1911-1912 (Box 46, Folder 2)
    - Gould Copper Mining Co. 1908-1912 (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - Gunsight Mine. 1886-1924 (Box 46, Folder 4)
    - Havalena Mining Co.: Minutes of meetings, etc., legal cases, involving O. K. Franklin. 1917-1920 (Box 46, Folder 5)
    - O. K. Franklin vs. Havalena Mining Co. 1912-1917 (Box 46, Folder 6)
    - Hector Copper Co. 1922-1926 (Box 46, Folder 7)
    - Isabel and Black Diamond Mining Claims. 1912-1925 (Box 46, Folder 8)
    - King of Arizona Co. 1900-1924 (Box 46, Folder 9)
    - Korn Kob Mining and Development Co. 1911-1913 (Box 46, Folder 10)
    - "Mexican" and "Emilia" Mining Claims. 1886-1892 (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - Mexican Mines: Legal case, P. Sandoval vs. Epes Randolph. 1906-1908 (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - Meyer-Clark-Rowe Mines Co. 1893-1907 (Box 47, Folder 3)
      Includes material about the Patterson and Iron Mountain Mining Claims, and a suit against Albert Steinfeld.
    - "Azurite Group" Mining Claims. 1901-1907 (Box 47, Folder 4)
    - Ocatea Copper Co. 1916-1917 (Box 47, Folder 5)
    - Ocatea Copper Co.: By-laws, Minutes of meetings. 1916-1918 (Box 47)
    - Ocatea Copper Co.: Stock Book. (Box 47)
    - Oro Mining Co. 1896-1899, 1913-1916 (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - Planchas de Plata Mines. 1889-1891 (Box 48, Folder 2)
    - "Poole Group" Mining Claims. 1896-1909 (Box 48, Folder 3)
      Includes legal case, R. N. Leatherwood vs. R. R. Richardson.
    - Portland Mining Co.: Legal cases, various. 1909-1916 (Box 48, Folder 4)
    - Portland Mining Co.: Legal case, A. J. McDonald, et al vs. J. T. McDonald, et al. 1912-1913 (Box 48, Folder 5)
    - Portland Mining Co.: Miscellaneous material. (Box 48, Folder 6)
    - Promontorio Consolidated Mining Co. 1907-1908 (Box 48, Folder 7)
    - Roadside Mine. 1906-1908 (Box 48, Folder 8)
    - Rosemont Copper Co. 1905-1908 (Box 48, Folder 9)
    - Salvator Mining and Milling Co. 1895-1898 (Box 48, Folder 10)
    - San Antonio-Arizona Mining Co. 1909-1912 (Box 48, Folder 11)
    - San Xavier Extension Copper Co. 1903, 1917-1918 (Box 48, Folder 12)
    - Silver King Mining Co. 1888-1890 (Box 48, Folder 13)
    - Silver Bell Copper Co.: Miscellaneous papers. 1903-1912 (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - Silver Bell Copper Co.: Legal case, Zeckendorf vs. Steinfeld. 1913-1914 (Box 49, Folder 2)
    - Silver Bell Copper Co.: Legal cases, various. 1903-1916 (Box 49, Folder 3)
    - Silver Hill Consolidated Copper Co. 1916-1920 (Box 49, Folder 4)
    - Silver Queen Mining Co. 1889-1905 (Box 49, Folder 5)
    - Fresnal Consolidated Gold Mines: Chiefly reports on the Monticell Group. 1918 (Box 49, Folder 6)
    - Silver Reef Mining Co. 1894-1906 (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - El Tajo Mining Co. 1916 (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - Tennessee Extension Mining Co. 1916-1920 (Box 50, Folder 3)
      Includes various mining claims involved in the Barnsdall Estate.
    - Jack Rabbit Mine. 1890-1903 (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - Tube City Mining and Milling Co. 1911-1913 (Box 50, Folder 5)
      Includes material on the Jack Rabbit Mine and suits of Zimmaran and P. Rider.
    - Union Basin Mining Co. 1913 (Box 50, Folder 6)
    - Weldon Gold and Copper Co. 1901-1903, 1908 (Box 50, Folder 7)
    - Wonder Mining Co.: Chief and Oriental Mining Claims. 1913 (Box 50, Folder 8)
    - Yaqui River Consolidated Gold and Copper Co. 1911-1925 (Box 50, Folder 9)
    - Vekol Mining and Milling Co. 1897-1904 (Box 50, Folder 10)
    - Vekol Range Copper Co.: Minutes, stockholders, correspondence. 1910-1916 (Box 50, Folder 11)
    - Vekol Range Copper Co.: Legal papers. 1910-1913 (Box 50, Folder 12)
    - Nogales Copper Co. 1903-1907 (Box 50, Folder 13)
    - Mining Correspondence: Arthur H. Elliott. 1893-1897 (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - Mining Correspondence: A. L. Harroun. 1916-1918 (Box 51, Folder 2)
    - Mining Correspondence: G. W. Norton. 1894-1899 (Box 51, Folder 3)
    - Southern Belle Mine. 1888-1889 (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - Total Wreck Mine: Correspondence of John O'Daugherty. 1888-1889 (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - Arizona Consolidated Gold & Silver Mining Co. 1889-1891 (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - Great Eastern Mines: Correspondence of Howell Hinds. 1889-1890 (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - "Gold Property at Dos Cabezas" and the "Casey Mine": Correspondence of P. B. McCabe. 1891-1901 (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - Lela Mining Co. 1892 (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - Christmas Gift Mine: Correspondence of Douglas Gray. 1893-1894 (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - Gold Hills Mining Co. 1893-1896 (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - Cababi Mines: Correspondence of J. Lucht. 1895-1896 (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - Whippoorwill Mine. 1896 (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - Table Mountain Group. 1896-1898 (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - Pride of the West Mine: Correspondence of Charles F. Kuhnen and others. 1896-1902 (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - Copper Glance Mine. 1897 (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - Old Glory Mine. 1897-1899 (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - San Carlos Copper Company Claims. 1900 (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - Mines in Copper Basin District, Yavapai County. 1900 (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - Sarah and other mining claims: Correspondence of L. Voelckel. 1900, 1909 (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - World's Fair Mines. 1904, 1919-1920 (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - 3R Mines. 1904-1920 (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - Saginaw Mines. 1902-1905 (Box 51, Folder 6)
    - Evening Glory Mining Claim. 1908 (Box 51, Folder 6)
    - Mining Claims in the Reed Mining District, Pima County. 1910 (Box 51, Folder 6)
    - Augusto Copper Mining Co.: C. B. Wilson vs. W. Kemp. 1910-1920 (Box 51, Folder 6)
    - Red Mountain Copper Co. 1916-1920 (Box 51, Folder 6)
    - Magnate Copper Co. 1918 (Box 51, Folder 6)
    - American Mine: Correspondence of Charles Hoff. 1919-1920 (Box 51, Folder 6)
    - Armagosa Mines: Correspondence of Lewis G. Davis. 1924 (Box 51, Folder 6)
    - M. P. Freeman vs. Tortilito Gold & Silver Mining Co. 1888 (Box 51, Folder 7)
    - Central Silver Mining Co.: Bowman vs. Losa. 1890-1901 (Box 51, Folder 7)
    - Irvin Mining Co.: McDonald vs. C. Swain. 1892-1894 (Box 51, Folder 7)
    - Jordan vs. Duke (Equator Case). 1896-1898 (Box 51, Folder 7)
    - Dragoon Mining Co. vs. Fitzgerald. 1899 (Box 51, Folder 7)
    - Guyjas Gold Mining Co.: L. Cable vs. N. & E. Bowlus. 1899-1901 (Box 51, Folder 7)
    - Vulcan #3 Mine: P. Schaaf vs. A Steinfeld. 1902-1903 (Box 51, Folder 8)
    - Paymaster Mine: W. M. Roberts vs. A. W. Lawrence, et al. 1903 (Box 51, Folder 8)
    - A. C. Simkins vs. Twin Buttes Mines. 1903-1907 (Box 51, Folder 8)
    - R. R. Richardson vs. Happy Jack Mining Co. 1904 (Box 51, Folder 8)
    - Various mines: A. C. Simkins vs. P. Contzen, et al. 1907 (Box 51, Folder 8)
    - O. Buckalew vs. Tip Top Copper Co. 1907 (Box 51, Folder 8)
    - Wallace, et al vs. Compania Minera Juarez S. A. 1910 (Box 51, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous mining correspondence. 1885-1927 (Box 52, Folder 1-4)
  - Land Grant Case Files, 1873-1924
    - Baca Float #3: Baca Will, Abstract of Title, deeds. (Box 53, Folder 1)
    - Baca Float #3: Correspondence. 1889-1916 (Box 53, Folder 2)
    - Baca Float #3: Bills and receipts. 1914-1917 (Box 53, Folder 2)
    - Baca Float #3: Correspondence. 1917-1920 (Box 53, Folder 3-4)
    - Baca Float #3: Legal case, State of Arizona vs. Watts, et al. 1914-1917 (Box 53, Folder 5)
      Includes related cases involving the Santa Cruz Development Co.
    - Baca Float #3: Robinson Land and Cattle Co., Silo Land and Cattle Co. 1918-1919 (Box 53, Folder 6)
    - Babacomari Land Grant: Correspondence. 1904-1912 (Box 53, Folder 7)
    - Babacomari Land Grant: Legal case, E. B. Perrin vs. R. Elias. 1876-1907 (Box 53, Folder 8)
    - Babacomari Land Grant: Legal case, S. Franklin vs. Empire Land and Cattle Co. 1907-1909 (Box 53, Folder 9)
    - Babacomari Land Grant: Legal case, E. B. Perrin vs. W. C. Greene. 1906-1907 (Box 53, Folder 9)
    - Babacomari Land Grant: S. Ainsa vs. R. Perrin, et al. 1892-1906 (Box 53, Folder 10)
    - U. S. Department of the Interior, Grant Confirmation. (Box 54, Folder 1)
    - Legal papers, maps, leasing account, etc. (Box 54, Folder 2)
    - F. Ely vs. New Mexico & Arizona Railroad Co. 1887-1892 (Box 54, Folder 3)
    - S. Ainsa vs. New Mexico & Arizona Railroad Co. 1892-1909 (Box 54, Folder 4-5)
    - S. Ainsa vs. E. L. Sanford, et al. 1909-1913 (Box 54, Folder 6)
    - C. J. Freese, et al, vs. T. Crespo, et al. 1886-1888 (Box 54, Folder 7)
    - S. Ainsa vs. Unknown Heirs of L. Herreros. 1903-1904 (Box 54, Folder 7)
    - S. Ainsa vs. The Southern Pacific Co. 1906-1907 (Box 54, Folder 7)
    - S. Ainsa vs. Crittenden Cattle Co., et al. 1907 (Box 54, Folder 7)
    - S. Ainsa vs. R. R. Richardson, et al. 1907 (Box 54, Folder 7)
    - R. R. Richardson vs. S. Ainsa. 1908 (Box 54, Folder 7)
    - S. Ainsa vs. James Gatlin, et al. 1909-1910 (Box 54, Folder 7)
    - R.R. Earhart vs. S. Ainsa. 1912, 1920 (Box 54, Folder 7)
    - Sonoita Land Grant: Correspondence. 1886-1924 (Box 55, Folder 1-5)
    - San Rafael de Valle Land Grant: Legal cases, S. Ainsa and J. P. Camou. 1873-1908 (Box 55, Folder 6)
    - San Rafael de la Zanja Land Grant: Legal case, J. E. Small vs. M. V. Corrella. 1888-1906 (Box 55, Folder 7)
    - San Juan de la Boquilla y Nogales Land Grant: Legal case, S. Ainsa vs. P. Hearst. 1889-1901 (Box 55, Folder 8)
    - Estate of Frank Ely. 1903-1914 (Box 56, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence: Ely, Herndon. 1903-1907 (Box 56, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, etc. regarding land grant cases (Chiefly with Santiago Ainsa). 1886-1911 (Box 56, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence: Cameron, Brewster and Colin. 1885-1920 (Box 57, Folder 1-7)
    - Correspondence: Ford, Rochester. 1888-1907 (Box 57, Folder 8-10)
  - Cattle Company Case Files, 1886-1920
    - "Y" Cattle Co.: Correspondence. 1895-1900 (Box 58, Folder 1-4)
    - "Y" Cattle Co.: First National Bank of Youngstown, Ohio, vs. W. H. Hurst, et al. (Box 58, Folder 5)
    - "Y" Cattle Co.: Financial papers. (Box 58, Folder 6)
    - "Y" Cattle Co.: Checks and stubs. (Box 58)
    - Arivaca Land and Cattle Co. 1889-1919 (Box 59, Folder 1)
    - Baboquivari Land and Cattle Co. 1895-1904 (Box 59, Folder 2)
      Includes suit of Appel vs. James.
    - Crittenden Land and Cattle Co.: Chiefly correspondence of R. R. Richardson. 1886-1899 (Box 59, Folder 3)
    - Empire Land and Cattle Co.: Chiefly correspondence of Walter Vail. 1890-1897 (Box 59, Folder 4)
    - La Osa Life Stock and Loan Co., La Osa Cattle Co. 1919 (Box 59, Folder 5)
    - Salero Live Stock and Land Co.: Legal cases, Lucas and Wise. 1894-1919 (Box 59, Folder 6)
    - San Pedro Cattle Co.: Legal case, A. G. Williams. 1890-1895 (Box 59, Folder 7)
    - West Coast Cattle Co.: Legal cases, H. M. Gidden, New York. 1915-1919 (Box 59, Folder 8)
    - Witbeck Land and Cattle Co. 1894-1899 (Box 59, Folder 9-10)
    - Courtney Ranch, Santa Cruz County: Legal case, Harrison vs. Renshaw. 1895-1911 (Box 59, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence and legal cases regarding cattle, ranches, etc. 1886-1920 (Box 59, Folder 12)
  - Canals and Irrigation Case Files, 1886-1919
    - Mohawk Canal, Farmers' Irrigating Canal Co. 1886-1894 (Box 60, Folder 1)
    - Mohawk Canal, Farmers' Irrigating Canal Co. & Palomas Canal Co. 1895-1900 (Box 60, Folder 2)
    - Florence Canal Co. and Casa Grande Canal Co. 1893-1898 (Box 60, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence regarding canals, irrigation projects, etc. 1888-1911 (Box 60, Folder 4)
    - "Southside property," Maricopa County: Correspondence. 1888-1919 (Box 60, Folder 5)
    - "Southside property," Maricopa County: Legal papers, cases, taxes. 1887-1918 (Box 60, Folder 6)
      Also includes material on the Southside Land and Water Co. and the Arizona Canal Co.
    - Correspondence: Schultz, T. L. 1887-1900 (Box 60, Folder 7)
    - Chenoweth vs. B. White, et al, Administrator of the Estate of T. Bayze. 1919 (Box 60, Folder 8)
  - Property Case Files, 1886-1931
    - Property tax cases in Nogales. 1889-1900 (Box 61, Folder 1)
      Suits involving:
      Henry O. Flipper
      Frank Main
      Eugene Wolff
      George B. Marsh
      J. K. Nolan
    - Nogales Property: Roy & Titcomb vs. J. Flin. 1905-1906 (Box 61, Folder 2)
    - Nogales Property: A. Dessart vs. Franklin & Saxon. 1907-1908 (Box 61, Folder 3)
    - Nogales Property: Leeker vs. Hammond. 1924-1925 (Box 61, Folder 4)
    - Nogales Property: Correspondence of E. Gaynor & others. 1887-1891 (Box 61, Folder 5)
    - Nogales Property: Meyers vs. de Tourniel. 1887, 1919 (Box 61, Folder 5)
    - Nogales Property: O. K. Franklin vs. J. Dessart. 1904 (Box 61, Folder 5)
    - Nogales Property: O. K. Franklin vs. T. Turner. 1904-1906 (Box 61, Folder 5)
    - Nogales Property: Bonynge vs. Dessart. 1905-1906 (Box 61, Folder 5)
    - Provident Mutual Building & Loan vs. Brickwood, et al. 1908 (Box 61, Folder 5)
    - Nogales Property: Ordinances for the town of Nogales. 1909 (Box 61, Folder 5)
    - Nogales Property: McIntyre vs. Neumann. 1909-1910 (Box 61, Folder 5)
    - Yuman Subdivision Property: Blaisdell vs. Steinfeld, et al. 1912-1914 (Box 61, Folder 6)
    - Winkelman Townsite Property: Willis & Pease vs. Heineman & Donau. 1910-1914 (Box 61, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence: Don Luis Townsite Co., Bisbee, Arizona. 1903-1905 (Box 61, Folder 8-9)
    - Don Luis Townsite Co. legal case with C. Hull. 1903-1905 (Box 61, Folder 10)
    - Tucson Property: Meyer Street and "Congress Hall", property of Charles O. Brown. 1892-1899 (Box 62, Folder 1)
    - Tucson Property: Hale vs. Hughes, Lot 1, Block 214. 1897-1900 (Box 62, Folder 2)
    - Tucson Property: H. B. Tenney vs. P. R. Tully, et al, Block 72. 1902 (Box 62, Folder 3)
    - Tucson Property: A. Steinfeld, et al, vs. R. Wood, et al, Block 133. 1903 (Box 62, Folder 4)
    - Tucson Property: F. Lexzynsky, et al, vs. City of Tucson, Block 206, "The Wedge." 1903-1905 (Box 62, Folder 5)
    - Tucson Property: A. Franklin vs. J. Howard, et al, Lot 11, Block 30. 1907 (Box 62, Folder 6)
    - Tucson Property: L. Matas vs. M. Costello, Lots 1 & 2, Block 197. 1906-1908 (Box 62, Folder 7)
    - Tucson Property: Concrete Construction Co. vs. C. Schell, Curb on 3rd St., between Stone and Park. 1911-1912 (Box 62, Folder 8)
    - Tucson Property: Tax suits involving S. Franklin, C. Christensen, R. Hopkins and J. Ivancovich, Lots 10 & 11, Block 92. 1903-1907 (Box 62, Folder 9)
    - Tucson Property: Garage building at 6th Ave., Lot 10, Block 92. 1916 (Box 62, Folder 10)